Mss.Rec.10 Mss.Rec.10
American Philosophical Society
Iroquois personal names
1951
Mss.Rec.10
American Philosophical Society
5.0 Reel(s)
These recordings consist of a reading of an alphabetical listing of approximately 6200 Iroquois personal names "in the Mohawk dialect" assembled by Charles A. Cooke (Thawennensere) from 1900-1951, and edited by Marius Barbeau.
5 sound tape reels (4 hr., 54 min.): analog, 3 3/4 ips, half track, mono; 5 in.
Cooke, Charles, 1870-1958
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Marius Barbeau in 1951.
Related Archival Materials
The accompanying manuscripts for these recordings is available in the Iroquois personal names collection (Mss.497.3.C772).
Barbeau, Marius, 1883-1969; Mohawk language; Names, Iroquois; Sound recordings
- Audio recordings
  - Ahaharas to Athenno, 1951-05; 01-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:32:58; Cooke, Charles
    Scope and Contents note
    An alphabetical list of Iroquoian proper names beginning with A, D, E, G, H, J, N, O, R, S, T, V, W, and Y, read by the collector in Mohawk. Introductory comments in English.
    Existence and Location of Originals note
    This file is a compressed, digitized version of the original. The APS Library maintains the original format (Sound tape reel) as well as an uncompressed digitized version of this recording.
    Mohawk language; Names, Mohawk
  - Ahtera to Deganyadarehgwen, 1951-05; 01-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:32:43; Cooke, Charles
    An alphabetical list of Iroquoian proper names beginning with A, D, E, G, H, J, N, O, R, S, T, V, W, and Y, read by the collector in Mohawk.
  - Continuation of names beginning with De, 1951-05; 02-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:32:29; Cooke, Charles
  - Conclusion of names beginning with D, beginning of E and G, 1951-05; 02-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:32:22; Cooke, Charles
  - Continuation of names begining with G, 1951-05; 03-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:32:21; Cooke, Charles
  - Conclusion of names beginning with G and H, 1951-05; 03-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:32:23; Cooke, Charles
  - Names beginning with J and O, 1951-05; 04-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:33:10; Cooke, Charles
  - Names beginning with O, R, and S, 1951-05; 04-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:33:05; Cooke, Charles
  - Names beginning with S, T, W, Y, 1951-05; 05-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:32:40; Cooke, Charles